Contact

jyotidabas91@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jyoti-dabassph-d-2b747083 (LinkedIn) github.com/jyotidabass (Personal)

Top Skills

Machine Learning
Deep Learning
Fuzzy Logic

Languages

Hindi, English, Sanskrit, Punjabi

Certifications

Build an App in Android Studio using Static Files

Building Smart Business Assistants with IBM Watson

Improve Efficiency in Asana for Project Managers

Python for Data Science and Al

Network Data Science with NetworkX and Python

Honors-Awards

Machine Learning Specialization https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/2RJU4KVXCW63

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate, https://www.coursera.org/ account/accomplishments/ specialization/certificate/ WGP85Q8B497Z

Al for Medicine Specialization

Introduction to Data Science Specialization

Applied Data Science Specialization

Publications

Proposed SRAM Cell Using Low Power Schmitt Trigger in Subthreshold Region Which Adapts Its Own Threshold

Jyoti Dabass, Ph.D

IIT Delhi|Sony Research|Data Science| Video,audio,speech, image processing| Fuzzy| Deep Learning|Computer Vision|Al Gurgaon, Haryana, India

Summary

Researcher, Engineer and Head of R&D team with interest in data science, analytics, marketing, computer vision, deep learning, fuzzy logic, machine learning, artificial intelligence, computer aided diagnosis, and natural language processing.

Career Highlights

- 1. Multidisciplinary academic background with qualification, research and teaching experience in computer, electrical and electronics engineering.
- 2. Top 1% of class during all educational degrees.
- 3. Completed higher education via competitive selections in public and private universities with educational fundings(scholarships) for the phd degree and bachelor's degree.
- 4.Earned certifications from 500+ MOOCs on data science, marketing, machine learning, deep learning, image processing, and related courses.
- 5. Worked with more than 100 learners in guiding/mentoring their thesis and projects in collaboration with Liverpool John Moore's University, UK and IIT Madras.
- 6. Collaborated and shared 800+ GitHub repositories.
- 7. Technical reviewer of 50 plus international journals and books. Reviewed more than 190 international publications.

github profile: https://github.com/jyotidabass

Semantic Scholar:https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/Jyoti-

Dabass/83462281

Publons profile: https://publons.com/researcher/3973927/jyoti-dabass/

Google Scholar profile: https://scholar.google.com/citations?

user=a7HGcrkAAAAJ&hl=en&oi=ao

Medium profile: medium. com/@jyoti_98875

Segmentation of Breast Density
Using K-Means Clustering Algorithm

Applications of Type II Fuzzy Sets-A Mathematical Review on Breast Cancer Imaging Modalities

Applications of Advanced Fuzzy Set in Medical Image Analysis: A Review

A hybrid U-Net model with attention and advanced convolutional learning modules for simultaneous gland segmentation and cancer grade prediction in colorectal histopathological images ** Feel free to reach out at jyotidabas91gmail.com for any assistance with Natural Language Processing, Machine learning, Data Science, Image Processing or Speech Processing, etc.

Experience

Buildnetic

Senior Al Scientist (Research and Development) April 2023 - Present (4 months)

upGrad

Thesis Supervisor/Subject Matter Expert and Instructor December 2021 - Present (1 year 8 months)

o Worked with more than 100 learners in guiding/mentoring their thesis and projects in collaboration with Liverpool John Moore's University, UK and IIT Madras.

SonyAl

Researcher

October 2022 - March 2023 (6 months)

- o Worked on data (text, image, audio and speech signals, techniques (supervised, unsupervised, reinforcement and meta-learning).
- o Contribution from data collection to product launch.
- o Contribution to patents, publications, collaborations and providing open source research solutions

Bajaj Capital Ltd Head- Image Processing January 2022 - September 2022 (9 months)

- Gurugram, Haryana, India
- o Worked on image and text datasets to provide personalized diet recommendation system.
- o Worked on stages from data collection to deployment of project.

The NorthCap University
Research Scholar
January 2017 - December 2021 (5 years)
Gurgaon, India

o Supervisors: Prof. Madasu Hanmandlu (IIT Delhi), Prof. Rekha Vig (NCU, Gurugram)

o Subject: Image Processing

o Remarks: Research work is focused on the analysis of breast cancer imaging modalities to detect Cancer. The main objective of the thesis are pre-processing (denoising, removal of background, pectoral muscles, labels etc. and enhancement), segmentation (clustering), feature extraction and classification using fuzzy, machine learning and deep learning techniques.

Education

2021)

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi
Postdoctoral Research Associate, Image Text Video and Audio
processing · (June 2022 - April 2023)

The NorthCap University

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Image Processing · (January 2017 - December

J.C. Bose University of Science and Technology, YMCA

Master of Technology - MTech, Electrical, Electronics and Communications

Engineering · (2014 - 2016)

Maharshi Dayanand University
Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electronics and communication engineering